insecure.org 2002-12-04

# Insecure.org Privacy Policy

Insecure.Org privacy policy  
(Also applies to related domains: Insecure.Com, Nmap.Org, Ncrack.Org, and Ncrack.Com)  
Insecure.Org respects and protects the privacy of individuals who use our services. Individually identifyable information about you is not willfully disclosed to any third party without first receiving your permission, as explained in this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy"). 

**Anonymous Browsing**

The vast majority of content on our sites does not require any sort of login and can be browsed anonymously. Of course, your IP address will be disclosed unless you use a proxy. 

**Cookies**

We may sometimes use cookies to better understand our user base and to improve the quality of our service. For example, we might someday use cookies to allow persistant logins. 

Security- and privacy-conscious people often disable cookies in their browser. We encourage people to do this. On Netscape 4.X, the option is available in the Edit -> Preferences -> Advanced menu. Other browsers offer similar options. 

**Security**

We recognize that privacy policies are ineffective if someone can break into the web and database servers and proceed to abuse the information. We constantly monitor public and private security lists (including [these](http://lists.insecure.org/)) to stay abreast of the latest security holes. Our software is designed with security as the #1 priority and our network is architected to maximise resilience to attacks. 

**Mailing lists**

We run several mailing lists such as [Nmap-hackers](http://lists.insecure.org/#nmap-hackers) and [Nmap-dev](http://lists.insecure.org/#nmap-dev). These are opt-in lists: you will only receive mail on them if you explicity sign up. Sign up email verification letters are sent to insure that one user cannot subscribe other people to the lists without their permission. Users can unsubscribe from the lists at any time using instructions sent when they subscribe and in the headers of each message. 

**Links to other sites**

This site contains links to other sites which are developed by people over whom we exercise no control. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such sites. 

**Public Forums**

This site makes chat rooms, forums, mailing lists, message boards, and/or news newsgroups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Mail disclosure**

Mail sent to us may occasionally be posted to the site or forwarded to other people (depending on the nature of the email). If you want to clarify that a certain email you send should be kept private, please say so in the email. We may post legal threats whether you want us to or not. 

**Traffic Data** Each time a visitor comes to our Web sites, our servers -- like most on the Web -- collect some basic technical information, including, for example, the visitor's domain name/IP address, referral data, and user-agent information. We also count, track and aggregate the visitor's activity into our analysis of general traffic flows at our sites (e.g. tracking where traffic comes from, how traffic flows within our sites, etc.). To these ends, we may merge information about visitors and visits into group data, which may then be shared on an aggregated basis with our advertisers; but we will not disclose your individual identity or personally identifiable data without your permission. When we do present aggregated information to outside companies, no one will be able to identify you or contact you. 

**Support requests and fingerprint submissions**

If you send us your IP address in a support request or fingerprint submission regarding our software, we may probe that address (including a port scan and OS detection) in order to answer your question or make use of the fingerprint submission. If you do not wish to have a machine probed, please say so or do not include the IP/hostname in the inforamtion you send us. 

**Surveys and other information requests**

We may occasionally post surveys and other forms requesting information. We will not share personally identifiable information from these forms unless we say otherwise on the survey/form. We may share aggregate data about the answers. For example, [here](http://lists.insecure.org/nmap-hackers/2000/Apr-Jun/0141.html) are the results of one of our surveys. 

**Your consent and changes to the privacy policy**

By using our web sites, you consent to the collection and use of your information as we have outlined in this policy. We may decide to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

**Contacting Insecure.Org**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact our privacy coordinator at [fyodor@insecure.org](mailto:fyodor@insecure.org).
